VLADYSLAV KRAMARENKO

236 992 9229 • Kramarenko.Vladyslav.92@gmail.com • Coquitlam, BC • linkedin.com/in/Vladyslav-Kramarenko

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Java Developer with 8 years of versatile software development, management, and IT leadership experience. Specializing in web applications and backend systems with Spring Boot and Hibernate. Proven success in IT project management, including accounting systems implementation and web development. Proficient in team leadership, market analysis, process improvement, and enhancing customer satisfaction.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Software: Jira, Jenkins, Postman, MySQL, Tomcat, Docker, AWS, MS Office, Photoshop, Figma. Programming Skills: Java, Python, HTML/CSS/JavaScript, SQL, XML, YAML, JSON, TypeScript.

Frameworks/Tools: Spring (Boot, Security, MVC), JPA, Mockito, Swagger, SonarQube, Bootstrap, JUnit, Git.

PORTFOLIO - KRAMARENKO.INFO

WORK EXPERIENCE

ZHYTLOBUD-2 ALC (Kharkiv, Ukraine) – Head of IT department

Dec 2020 - Current

- Managed a diverse team of six IT professionals and various contractors, overseeing the development and management of various websites using PHP, WordPress, and JavaScript across a city-wide organization.
- Automated document flow for the transport department by integrating the "1C" accounting system with concrete node software, GPS vehicle monitoring, and car weights, improving operational efficiency and data accuracy.
- Integrated the G-Plus CRM System, centralizing data management, and incorporating telephony systems.

JUST CAT (Kharkiv, Ukraine) - CEO / Founder

Aug 2017 - Dec 2022

- Established and led a successful wood pellet manufacturing business, targeting the pet litter market.

ZHYTLOBUD-2 ALC (Kharkiv, Ukraine) – Project Manager

Nov 2018 - Dec 2020

- Implemented 1C accounting system for a construction company with over 1,000 employees.
- Led the Creation of Android & iOS complexes catalogue applications with interactive apartment designs.
- Created Java program for daily mixer route planning, streamlining processes and boosting department efficiency.

ECOFUELTRADE LLC (Kharkiv, Ukraine) – CEO / Co-Founder

Sep 2015 - Sep 2017

- Established a new biofuel manufacturer producing up to 100 tons of pellets per month with 10 employees.
- Controlled finances, organized operations, conducted market analysis, managed WordPress website.

FREELANCE (USA/Ukraine) – Java Web Developer

Sep 2011 - Sep 2012

- Developed a website for playing radio-controlled cars with video, using a console Java application for Arduino. Backend: Java, JSP, Spring MVC, and Maven; Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery

EDUCATION

National Technical University "Kharkiv Polytechnic Institute" (Kharkiv, Ukraine)

Sep 2013 - Jun 2013

Master of Project Management

Implemented a Java-based forecasting software for modeling and predicting scientific and technological development in Ukraine's industry, using simulation models and inter-sectoral interactions.

National Technical University "Kharkiv Polytechnic Institute" (Kharkiv, Ukraine) Bachelor of Computer Science

Sep 2009 – Jun 2013

CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

EPAM SYSTEMS (Remote) – External Java Lab

Feb 2023 - Jul 2023

- Enhanced proficiency in Spring Boot, Security, MVC, and SQL, utilized JPA/Hibernate for data management.
- Implemented RESTful APIs. Applied AWS services (S3, EC2, RDS). Incorporated CI/CD with Jenkins.
- Gained experience creating Frontend with TypeScript and Angular.

EPAM SYSTEMS (Remote) - IT Marathon

Nov 2022 - Dec 2022

- Broadening my skill set in software architecture, business analysis, Java, .Net, JS, TS coding, and UX/UI design using Figma. Built a web-based Tic-Tac-Toe application leveraging AWS Lambda, Redis and DynamoDB.

EPAM SYSTEMS (Remote) - Java Spring-Summer 2022

June 2022 - Dec 2022

- Enhanced proficiency in full-stack Java development, including servlets, adeptly managed databases, and effectively worked with XML data using foundational skills in Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, and MySQL.